Serdar Selim Yesildag

Summary

Data Analyst with 8 years of professional experience in international development sector and humanitarian assistance operations, specializing in quantitative and qualitative analysis for project monitoring and evaluation, data collection and information management solutions, production of business intelligence dashboards and reporting suites.

Education

Northeastern University, Vancouver. 2024 — Ongoing Masters of Professional Studies in Analytics.

California State University, Chico. 2007 — 2011

Bachelors of Arts in Economics and International Relations.

Languages

English (Fluent), Spanish (intermediate), Turkish (Native)

Info

Phone: (+1) 672 963-9698

Email: serdarselimys@gmail.com **Website:** serdarselimys.github.io

Nationality: Turkish

Current Location: Vancouver, BC, Canada.

Professional Experience

United Nations World Food Programme

Research, Assessment and Monitoring Officer, Freetown, Sierra Leone Country Office.

Sep 2022 — Aug 2023

- Managed the implementation of household level food security surveys and analyzed the results for supporting programmatic design and update process of WFP operations and wider humanitarian stakeholders in Sierra Leone.
- Supervised post distribution monitoring surveys and established continues activity implementation monitoring to track the progress of project indicators at outcome and output levels.
- Conducted research on market price trends and macro economic indicators investigating underlying causes of changes in food insecurity levels and obstacles restraining the development of local agricultural sector and food production supply chains.
- Assessed the monitoring and evaluation capacity of the Country Office, identified gaps and provided solutions that are compliant with corporate standards including the minimum monitoring requirements (MMR), standard operational procedures (SOP) for establishing an annual country office monitoring plan.
- Managed digitalization of data collection, analysis and reporting processes for efficient and effective reporting of output and outcome indicators to facilitate technical analysis, interpretation and information management.

Data Analyst, Corporate Planning and Performance Division, Rome HQ.

Oct 2021 — Aug 2022

- Analyzed data from WFP humanitarian operations over 80 countries contained in various data repositories such as COMET and DOTs for monitoring corporate KPIs and informing decision making process at management level.
- Managed various corporate dashboards that analyses WFP global operational data for corporate activity output reporting pertaining to over 4 million metric tons of food and 3.3 billion USD cash based transfers to 120 million beneficiaries worldwide.
- Designed a suite of dashboards for reporting various dimensions of global WFP assistance operations focusing on assistance delivery metrics, caloric value estimates and expenditures per beneficiary measurements.
- Ensured that the corporate dashboards are timely updated and aligned with WFP's corporate reporting standards and guidelines.
- Provided guidance to WFP Regional Bureaus and Country offices for food distribution reconciliation process, supporting corporate accountability activities and ensuring sound reporting of food movements between WFP and it's cooperating partners.

- Analyzed periodic survey data for studying the living conditions of 3.6 million Syrian refugees living in Turkey for drafting internal and external reports.
- Managed and led the implementation of 450+ focus group discussions across 7 field offices with the participation of over 4000 Syrian refugees.
- Created internal dashboards for tracking the progress of project monitoring activities such as vulnerability assessments, food security surveys and field visits across 80 provinces of Turkey.
- Maintained surveys databases for ensuring all questionnaires used by field staff are up to date and entries are accurately recorded for 6 main studies containing over 80,000 survey entries.

Administration Assistant, Ankara, Turkey Country Office.

Sep 2016 — July 2017

- Provided office administrative services such as facilities maintenance, travel, and light vehicle fleet management to 185 staff across 7 field offices.
- Digitalized administrative request mechanisms via implementing web forms for ensuring sound execution of operating procedures and sound record keeping.

Investment Support and Promotion Agency of Turkey

Project Director, Public Private Partnerships Unit, Istanbul.

Aug 2012 — May 2015

- Conducted market intelligence research and supply chain analysis of various sectors to identify potential opportunities for foreign direct investments.
- Identified sectors and prioritized promotion activities for investment areas with the highest potential for supporting economic development.
- Contributed to formulation of national strategic action plans for promoting emerging investment opportunities in USA and Spain.
- Drafted info-notes and content for sectoral policy reports to inform the national policy-making process related to foreign direct investments.
- Represented the agency at national and international conferences and organized B2B meetings between local and international corporations for exploring possible joint ventures, merger and acquisition processes.

Technical Competencies

- ♦ Research
- Survey Design
- Quantitative and Qualitative Analysis
- Report Writing
- ♦ Information Management
- Business Analytics
- ♦ Data Visualization

Software Proficiencies

- **♦** Tableau
- ♦ SPSS
- Python
- ♦ Palantir Foundry Platform
- ♦ SQL
- ♦ Open Data Kit, Kobo Toolbox
- ♦ Microsoft Office Suite